James R. Priest

5111 Princess Anne Road, La Cañada, CA 91011 • Cell 626-240-9970 Email james-priest@outlook.com • Website james-priest.github.io

SUMMARY

Full Stack React.js, .NET, Node.js, Database Developer with 20 years of experience building web applications.

SKILLS

Language: JavaScript, C#, SQL, Regular Expressions Web: HTML5, CSS3, DOM, Bootstrap, REST API Database: SQL Server, MySQL, NoSQL, MongoDB **IDE:** VS Code, Visual Studio, Chrome Developer Tools Cloud: Firebase, AWS, Azure DevOps, RestDB.io

Build: NPM, Grunt, Gulp, Webpack, Parcel, Yeoman

Framework: React.js, Redux, ASP.NET, Node.js, jQuery

UI Design: Responsive UI/UX, Accessibility

Data: Stored Procedures, Functions, Triggers, Views Distributed Version Control: Git, GitHub, SVN

Hosting: Netlify, Heroku, Azure Web

Static Site Generator: Gatsby, Jekyll, GitHub Pages

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Web Application Developer / Technology Director Velodea

Pasadena, CA

04/2006 - 03/2017

- Served as Solutions Architect, Programming Lead, and Database Developer for digital marketing firm.
- Successfully built over 70 website solutions and marketing campaigns for Fortune 500 companies, including Shell, Qualcomm, Sprint, Maserati, Fox, Miramax, ABC, J. Walter Thompson, and Edelman.
- Designed large-scale learning management system to track and schedule education of 85,000 students.

Lead Developer, Founder

La Cañada, CA

devAware Technology Solutions

07/2002 - 03/2006

- Excelled in building custom Web, Windows, and .NET application systems for various corporate clients.
- Hired by Sony to build advanced kiosk application for VIAO laptops, with successful nationwide rollout.
- Engineered web and desktop platforms to promote major motion picture releases for Fox and Miramax.

Lead Software Developer

Milan, Italy and Los Angeles, CA

The Velodea Group / Bleu22 Studios

07/2000 - 07/2002

- Led the product development team of multi-national digital start-up in Milan and Los Angeles.
- Developed real-time web analytics platform to provide behavioral tracking and custom reporting.
- Built proprietary asset and client management systems, licensed by Sony, Qualcomm, and Shell Oil.

Release Program Manager

Redmond, WA

Microsoft

11/1998 – 06/2000

- Designed mission-critical app suite to manage thousands of software releases to the web each month.
- Built web-based training system to provide CBT to employees and non-technical business owners.
- Engineered tracking and query system to manage media shipments of software to third-party vendors.

CERTIFICATIONS

React Nanodegree (*React, Redux, React Native*), Udacity 6-month term June 2019 6-month term October 2018 Google Mobile Web Specialist Nanodegree, Udacity JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures, freeCodeCamp 300 hours December 2017 Responsive Web Design, freeCodeCamp 300 hours July 2017

EDUCATION

DeVry University Pomona, CA

James R. Priest

5111 Princess Anne Road, La Cañada, CA 91011 • Cell 626-240-9970 Email james-priest@outlook.com • Website james-priest.github.io

RECENT PROJECTS

Mobile Flashcards - App

June 2019

GitHub: https://bit.ly/2MTVhSc Live Demo: https://bit.ly/2FhBE06

May 2019

Triathlon Fitness Tracker - App

GitHub: https://bit.ly/2KqJE3i Live Demo: https://bit.ly/2Irc8aY



React Native, Redux, React Navigation, Redux Thunk, Expo, Animations, Notifications



React Native, Redux, React Navigation, Geolocation, Notifications, Expo

Would You Rather - Game

April 2019

GitHub: https://bit.ly/2MVL2Ng Live Demo: https://bit.ly/2RkLflc **Restaurant Reviews - App** GitHub: https://bit.ly/2x1xwwL Live Demo: https://bit.ly/2KYE0EJ



React, Redux, React Router, Redux Thunk, Auth, REST API, RestDB, Semantic-UI-React



PWA, IndexedDB, Cache API, Promise API, Service Worker, REST API, RestDB

CSS Grid Learning - App

June 2018

GitHub: https://bit.ly/2WR0Gcz Live Demo: https://bit.ly/2KpZ3AB



JavaScript ES6, CSS3 Animations, RegEx, Advanced DOM Manipulation

Weather Forecast - App

March 2018

December 2018

GitHub: https://bit.ly/2lphkM8 Live Demo: https://bit.ly/2MRbgQP



HTML5, Geolocation API, Semantic UI, CSS3 Animations, Async Web API